<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>End-to-End on Manabie Tech Blog</title><link>/tags/end-to-end/</link><description>Recent content in End-to-End on Manabie Tech Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Except where otherwise noted, content on this site is licensed under a [Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International license](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/).</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 17:46:06 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/end-to-end/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to use Playwright in cucumberjs</title><link>/2021/12/how-to-use-playwright-in-cucumberjs/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 10:45:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>/2021/12/how-to-use-playwright-in-cucumberjs/</guid><description>In our previous blog article HERE, we explained why we&amp;rsquo;re using Cucumber for E2E test at Manabie, and provided a brief understanding about Cucumber.
This time, let&amp;rsquo;s dive a little bit deeper!
Before we start, let&amp;rsquo;s cover a brief introduction to Cucumber again, and afterward, about Playwright.
Cucumber Cucumber is a tool that supports Behaviour-Driven Development(BDD), If you’re new to Behaviour-Driven Development read BDD introduction first.
Cucumberjs is an open-source software testing tool written in Javascript, while the tests are written in Gherkin, a non-technical and human-readable language.</description></item><item><title>Why we use Cucumber for end-to-end testing?</title><link>/2021/12/why-we-use-cucumber-for-end-to-end-testing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 14:37:23 +0700</pubDate><guid>/2021/12/why-we-use-cucumber-for-end-to-end-testing/</guid><description>Why we use Cucumber for end-to-end testing? Before getting to know why we use cucumber for End-to-end testing. Let&amp;rsquo;s understand what&amp;rsquo;s end-to-end testing and cucumber are.
What is End to end testing? End to end testing (E2E testing) is a software testing method that validates the entire software. From the beginning to the end.
The purpose of end-to-end testing is to simulate how a real user interacts with the application, list out the scenarios, and test the whole software for dependencies, data integrity and communication with other systems, interfaces, network connectivity and databases to exercise complete production like scenario.</description></item></channel></rss>